<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on José Ignacio Orlando</title>
    <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/tags/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on José Ignacio Orlando</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 José Ignacio Orlando</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/news/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>NVIDIA Hardware Grant</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-nvidia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-nvidia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My application to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.nvidia.com/academic_gpu_seeding&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NVIDIA GPU Grant&lt;/a&gt; was accepted! As part of this grant, I will receive a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/titan/titan-xp/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NVIDIA Titan XP GPU&lt;/a&gt; to perform my research on deep learning techniques for OCT image analysis. I would really like to thank the NVIDIA Corporation for providing me with this cutting-edge hardware that will certainly help me to improve the efficiency of my methods.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to Vienna!</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-optima/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-optima/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad to tell you, guys, that since next week I will be formally part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://optima.meduniwien.ac.at/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Christian Doppler Laboratory for Ophthalmic Image Analysis (OPTIMA)&lt;/a&gt;, a multidisciplinary research team that belongs to the Department of Ophthalmology and Optometry of the Medical University of Vienna (Austria). I&amp;rsquo;m joining the laboratory as a Postdoctoral Research Associate, working on automated OCT image analysis using deep learning techniques. My research will be funded by the project WWTF AugUniWien / FA746A0249. I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to start to work with this amazing team!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve defended my PhD thesis!</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-phd-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-phd-defense/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, September 21th 2017, I have officially defended my PhD thesis!! It was entitled &amp;ldquo;Machine learning for ophthalmic screening and diagnostics from fundus images&amp;rdquo;. You can find its English version &lt;a href=&#34;https://lirias.kuleuven.be/bitstream/123456789/592162/1/tesis.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and the Spanish version &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ridaa.unicen.edu.ar/xmlui/handle/123456789/1476&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Most of the code of each of the contributions is available on my github profile. Feel free to clone the repositories and experiment with them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to thank my supervisors, Matthew and Mariana, for guiding me through all this years. I would also like to thank the members of the jury, Prof. Dr. José M. Massa, Prof. Dra. Virginia Ballarin and Prof. Dr. Pablo Granitto, for carefully reading the thesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I will continue working as a postdoc at PLADEMA, until 2018, when I&amp;rsquo;m leaving to Vienna to join the Christian Doppler Laboratory for Ophthalmic Image Analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
