<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on José Ignacio Orlando</title>
    <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/tags/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on José Ignacio Orlando</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 José Ignacio Orlando</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ignaciorlando.github.io/tags/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation at UBA</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-uba-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-uba-presentation/</guid>
      <description>In December 7th I gave a lecture on machine learning for ophthalmic image analysis at the University of Buenos Aires (UBA, Argentina). This talk was part of the closure event of the &amp;ldquo;Deep Learning for Medical Image Analysis&amp;rdquo; course that Enzo Ferrante taught at the Faculty of Exact Sciences. Thanks Enzo for the invitation!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REFUGE: Retinal Fundus Glaucoma Challenge</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-refuge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-refuge/</guid>
      <description>We kindly invite you to participate in the REFUGE challenge on glaucoma detection in fundus images, as part of the Ophthalmic Medical Image Analysis (OMIA) workshop at MICCAI 2018 in Granada (Spain).
The deadline for submitting your results on the validation set either for glaucoma detection, optic disc/cup segmentation and/or fovea detection is this Friday 28th!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our paper was accepted for MICCAI 2018!</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-miccai-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-miccai-2018/</guid>
      <description>Our paper entitled &amp;ldquo;Towards a glaucoma risk index based on simulated hemodynamics from fundus images&amp;rdquo; has been accepted for presentation in MICCAI 2018! In this article we present one of the first attempts to characterize the hemodynamics of the retinal arterioles og glaucomatous patients. To this end, we have used a 0D model for simulating the blood flow in patient specific segmentations of the arteries, and proposed a novel dictionary-learning based strategy for summarizing all the hemodynamic outcomes into a fixed length feature vector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NVIDIA Hardware Grant</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-nvidia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-nvidia/</guid>
      <description>My application for the NVIDIA GPU Grant was accepted! As part of this grant, I will receive a NVIDIA Titan XP GPU to perform my research on deep learning techniques for OCT image analysis. I would really like to thank the NVIDIA Corporation for providing me with this cutting-edge hardware that will certainly help me to improve the efficiency of my methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to Vienna!</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-optima/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-optima/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m glad to tell you, guys, that since next week I will be formally part of the Christian Doppler Laboratory for Ophthalmic Image Analysis (OPTIMA), a multidisciplinary research team that belongs to the Department of Ophthalmology and Optometry of the Medical University of Vienna (Austria). I&amp;rsquo;m joining the laboratory as a Postdoctoral Research Associate, working on automated OCT image analysis using deep learning techniques. My research will be funded by the project WWTF AugUniWien / FA746A0249.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve defended my PhD thesis!</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-phd-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-phd-defense/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, September 21th 2017, I have officially defended my PhD thesis!! It was entitled &amp;ldquo;Machine learning for ophthalmic screening and diagnostics from fundus images&amp;rdquo;. You can find its English version here, and the Spanish version here. Most of the code of each of the contributions is available on my github profile. Feel free to clone the repositories and experiment with them!
I would like to thank my supervisors, Matthew and Mariana, for guiding me through all this years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>