<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>José Ignacio Orlando</title>
    <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on José Ignacio Orlando</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 José Ignacio Orlando</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ignaciorlando.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/home/about/</guid>
      <description>Biography Hi there! I&amp;rsquo;m José Ignacio Orlando, but you can call me Nacho :) I&amp;rsquo;m currently an Assistant Researcher from CONICET, working as part of Yatiris lab at the PLADEMA Institute (UNICEN - CIC-PBA - CNEA, Tandil, Argentina). Apart from PLADEMA (where I did my PhD from 2013 to 2017), my previous affiliations include the Center for Learning and Visual Computing in Paris, France (2013, 6 months working as an intern funded by INRIA), ESAT-PSI in KU Leuven, Belgium (2016, 1 month working as a visiting scholar) and the Christian Doppler Laboratory for Ophthalmic Image Analysis (OPTIMA) from the Medical University of Vienna, Austria (2018-2019, almost 2 years working as a postdoctoral researcher).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent publications</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/home/publications_selected/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/home/publications_selected/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/home/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/home/publications/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/home/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/home/talks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Posts</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/home/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/home/posts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/home/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/home/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/home/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/home/teaching/</guid>
      <description>I have been a Teaching Assistant in the following courses at UNICEN (Argentina):
 Workshop on Medical Image Analysis (2014-2018) Workshop on Computational Mathematics (2015-2018) Information Theory (2013-2016) Software Development Methodologies (2010-2012)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/home/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convocatoria para Postulantes a Becas Doctorales CONICET 2020 y CIC-PBA 2020</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/_open-position-2020-conicet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/_open-position-2020-conicet/</guid>
      <description>Resumen Estamos buscando aspirantes para postular a las becas doctorales de CONICET y/o CIC-PBA 2020, para incorporarse en un proyecto enfocado en el desarrollo de métodos basados en deep learning para analizar automáticamente imágenes de la retina y ayudar a los médicos a obtener mejores diagnósticos de algunas enfermedades visuales.
Buscamos graduados/as o alumnos/as avanzados/as de carreras informáticas como Ingeniería de Sistemas, de Software o de Informática, o Licenciatura en Informática o Ciencias de la Computación, y afines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convocatoria para Estudiantes Avanzados de Ingeniería - Becas INI 2020</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/open-position-2020-ini/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/open-position-2020-ini/</guid>
      <description>Resumen Estamos entrevistando estudiantes avanzados de Ingeniería de Sistemas para aplicar a las Becas de Ingreso a la Investigación (INI) 2020&amp;frasl;2021 de la Secretaría de Ciencia, Arte y Tecnología (SECAT) de la UNICEN. Estas becas te aseguran una remuneración de $4500 mensuales que por trabajar 10 horas semanales durante 1 año en un proyecto de investigación específico, con la ayuda de un/a director/a. Los resultados de tu trabajo podés usarlos después como tesis de grado e incluso como prácticas profesionales supervisadas (PPS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation @ IMAGE AI in Leuven (Belgium)</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2019-12-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2019-12-12/</guid>
      <description>In December 12th I participated (remotely) as a lecturer at IMAGE AI, an international meeting on artificial intelligence and its application to glaucoma, organized by the European Glaucoma Society in collaboration with researchers from UZ Leuven and VITO. I was invited to present the results of the challenge REFUGE, in whose organization I participated during my postdoc in Austria. The slides can be found here. This work is a collaboration between Yanwu Xu, Hrvoje Bogunović, Huazhu Fu, Xiualn Zhang, Fei Li and the REFUGE team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s next in AI for glaucoma screening? The REFUGE challenge outcomes</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/talk/imageia2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/talk/imageia2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An amplified-target loss approach for photoreceptor layer segmentation in pathological OCT scans</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/omia-photoreceptors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/omia-photoreceptors/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foveal Avascular Zone Segmentation in Clinical Routine Fluorescein Angiographies Using Multitask Learning</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/omia-faz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/omia-faz/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REFUGE Challenge: A Unified Framework for Evaluating Automated Methods for Glaucoma Assessment from Fundus Photographs</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/media-refuge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/media-refuge/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convocatoria para Estudiantes Avanzados de Ingeniería - EVC-CIN 2019</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/open-position-2019-cin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/open-position-2019-cin/</guid>
      <description>Resumen Estamos entrevistando estudiantes avanzados de Ingeniería de Sistemas para aplicar a las Becas de Estímulo a las Vocaciones Científicas (EVC) del Consejo Universitario Nacional (CIN). Estas becas te permiten trabajar 12 horas semanales durante 12 meses en un proyecto de investigación específico, con la ayuda de un/a director/a. Los resultados de tu trabajo podés usarlos después como tesis de grado, o como un punto de apoyo para más adelante hacer un postgrado.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving back to Argentina</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2019-09-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2019-09-01/</guid>
      <description>In September 13th I&amp;rsquo;ll be landing in Argentina to be once again part of PLADEMA, this time as an Assistant Researcher funded by CONICET. I&amp;rsquo;ll be joining again Yatiris, a group within PLADEMA developing cutting edge technologies for medical image analysis using computer vision, machine learning and pattern recognition techniques. I&amp;rsquo;ll be responsible of coordinating all the deep learning initiatives, while continuing my own line of research in computer-assisted ophthalmology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Orthogonal Projections for Dimension Reduction and Applications in Augmented Target Loss Functions for Learning Problems</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/jmiv-orthogonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/jmiv-orthogonal/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our paper was accepted for IJCARS!</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2019-07-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2019-07-30/</guid>
      <description>Our paper entitled &amp;ldquo;Improving realism in patient specific Ultrasound simulation using CycleGANs&amp;rdquo; has been accepted for publication in the International Journal of Computer Assisted Radiology and Surgery (IJCARS)! In this article we present a hybrid approach towards US simulation that combines ray-casting techniques with CycleGANs. The key idea is to use these generative models to alleviate the drawback of current available simulation techniques. In particular, traditional ray-casting based solutions for US simulation usually fail to model complex features such as artifacts or attenuations that are typical from this imaging modality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiclass segmentation as multitask learning for drusen segmentation in retinal optical coherence tomography</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/miccai-drusen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/miccai-drusen/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our paper was accepted for MICCAI!</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2019-06-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2019-06-05/</guid>
      <description>Our paper entitled &amp;ldquo;Multiclass segmentation as multitask learning for drusen segmentation in retinal optical coherence tomography&amp;rdquo; has been accepted for publication at MICCAI 2019! Drusen segmentation in OCT is a challenging task. In general, it is posed either as a binary segmentation problem (drusen vs. everything else) or as a layer segmentation problem (by detecting the outer boundary of the RPE and the Bruch&amp;rsquo;s membrane). Each approach has its advantages and disadvantages: binary segmentation might be prone to false positives in areas that are not anatomically plausible, while layer segmentation might fail under the presence of large drusenoid deposits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting Epistemic Uncertainty of Anatomy Segmentation for Anomaly Detection in Retinal OCT</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/tmi-anomaly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/tmi-anomaly/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U2-Net: A Bayesian U-Net Model with Epistemic Uncertainty Feedback for Photoreceptor Layer Segmentation in Pathological OCT Scans</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/talk/isbi2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/talk/isbi2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultrasound simulation</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/project/us-simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/project/us-simulation/</guid>
      <description>Ultrasound (US) is a fast, low cost imaging technique that is widely use in emergency rooms. As part of this project, we are developing an automated system for US simulation, that allows to produce realistic US scans from segmented CT volumes of real patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two papers accepted for ISBI 2019!</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-12-18-isbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-12-18-isbi/</guid>
      <description>Excellent news to finish an amazing year of work at OPTIMA! We got two papers accepted for presentation at ISBI 2019 :)
&amp;ldquo;U2-Net: A Bayesian U-Net model with epistemic uncertainty feedback for photoreceptor layer segmentation in pathological OCT scans&amp;rdquo; describes a novel U-shaped architecture for photoreceptor layer segmentation in OCT scans. We modified the basic U-Net with LeakyReLUs, batch normalization and dropout to improve the original segmentation performance. Additionally, we used epistemic uncertainty estimation based on Monte Carlo sampling with dropout on test time to provide qualitative feedback about potential errors of the network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving realism in patient-specific abdominal Ultrasound simulation using CycleGANs</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/ijcars-us-simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/ijcars-us-simulation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U2-Net: A Bayesian U-Net model with epistemic uncertainty feedback for photoreceptor layer segmentation in pathological OCT scans</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/isbi-uncertainty/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/isbi-uncertainty/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using CycleGANs for effectively reducing image variability across OCT devices and improving retinal fluid segmentation</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/isbi-cyclegan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/isbi-cyclegan/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning for ophthalmic image analysis</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/talk/uba2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/talk/uba2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation at UBA</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-12-07-uba-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-12-07-uba-presentation/</guid>
      <description>In December 7th I gave a lecture on machine learning for ophthalmic image analysis at the University of Buenos Aires (UBA, Argentina). This talk was part of the closure event of the &amp;ldquo;Deep Learning for Medical Image Analysis&amp;rdquo; course that Enzo Ferrante taught at the Faculty of Exact Sciences. Thanks Enzo for the invitation!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REFUGE: Retinal Fundus Glaucoma Challenge</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-07-24-refuge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-07-24-refuge/</guid>
      <description>We kindly invite you to participate in the REFUGE challenge on glaucoma detection in fundus images, as part of the Ophthalmic Medical Image Analysis (OMIA) workshop at MICCAI 2018 in Granada (Spain).
The deadline for submitting your results on the validation set either for glaucoma detection, optic disc/cup segmentation and/or fovea detection is this Friday 28th!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our paper was accepted for MICCAI 2018!</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-05-25-miccai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-05-25-miccai/</guid>
      <description>Our paper entitled &amp;ldquo;Towards a glaucoma risk index based on simulated hemodynamics from fundus images&amp;rdquo; has been accepted for presentation in MICCAI 2018! In this article we present one of the first attempts to characterize the hemodynamics of the retinal arterioles og glaucomatous patients. To this end, we have used a 0D model for simulating the blood flow in patient specific segmentations of the arteries, and proposed a novel dictionary-learning based strategy for summarizing all the hemodynamic outcomes into a fixed length feature vector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NVIDIA Hardware Grant</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-02-14-nvidia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-02-14-nvidia/</guid>
      <description>My application for the NVIDIA GPU Grant was accepted! As part of this grant, I will receive a NVIDIA Titan XP GPU to perform my research on deep learning techniques for OCT image analysis. I would really like to thank the NVIDIA Corporation for providing me with this cutting-edge hardware that will certainly help me to improve the efficiency of my methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to Vienna!</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-01-01-optima/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-01-01-optima/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m glad to tell you, guys, that since next week I will be formally part of the Christian Doppler Laboratory for Ophthalmic Image Analysis (OPTIMA), a multidisciplinary research team that belongs to the Department of Ophthalmology and Optometry of the Medical University of Vienna (Austria). I&amp;rsquo;m joining the laboratory as a Postdoctoral Research Associate, working on automated OCT image analysis using deep learning techniques. My research will be funded by the project WWTF AugUniWien / FA746A0249.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated retinal OCT analysis</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/project/oct-image-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/project/oct-image-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Optical coherence tomography (OCT) is a 3D non-invasive imaging technique that allows to inspect the retina at a micrometric resolution. It is widely applied in ophthalmology for diagnosis and treatment planning of several diseases, including diabetic macular edema, retinal vein occlusion and age-related macular degeneration. In this project we are focused in introducing automated techniques for precision medicine based in this imaging modality. To this end, we develop methods for characterizing the status of the photoreceptors and to segment lesions and other abnormalities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards a glaucoma risk index based on simulated hemodynamics from fundus images</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/miccai-hemodynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/miccai-hemodynamics/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retinal blood vessel segmentation in high resolution fundus photographs using automated parameter estimation</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/talk/sipaim2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/talk/sipaim2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retinal blood vessel segmentation in high resolution fundus photographs using automated feature parameter estimation</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/sipaim-highres/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/sipaim-highres/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Ensemble Deep Learning Based Approach for Red Lesion Detection in Fundus Images</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/cmpb-redlesions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/cmpb-redlesions/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve defended my PhD thesis!</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2017-09-22-phd-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2017-09-22-phd-defense/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, September 21th 2017, I have officially defended my PhD thesis!! It was entitled &amp;ldquo;Machine learning for ophthalmic screening and diagnostics from fundus images&amp;rdquo;. You can find its English version here, and the Spanish version here. Most of the code of each of the contributions is available on my github profile. Feel free to clone the repositories and experiment with them!
I would like to thank my supervisors, Matthew and Mariana, for guiding me through all this years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Discriminatively Trained Fully Connected Conditional Random Field Model for Blood Vessel Segmentation in Fundus Images</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/tbme-vessels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/tbme-vessels/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proliferative Diabetic Retinopathy Characterization based on Fractal Features: Evaluation on a Publicly Available Data Set</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/medphys-fractals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/medphys-fractals/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convolutional neural network transfer for automated glaucoma identification</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/sipaim-glaucoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/sipaim-glaucoma/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of image features for vessel wall segmentation in intravascular ultrasound images</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/ijcars-ivus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/ijcars-ivus/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning fully-connected CRFs for blood vessel segmentation in retinal images</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/miccai-vessels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/publication/miccai-vessels/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated fundus image analysis</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/project/fundus-image-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/project/fundus-image-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Fundus photography is a low cost medical imaging technique that allows to assess the retina non-invasively. As part of this project we develop automated tools based on deep learning and image processing techniques to aid clinicians in low cost screening of retinal diseases such as diabetic retinopathy, glaucoma and age-related macular degeneration. We have created methods for automatically segmenting red lesions in diabetic retinopathy cases and for characterizing the hemodynamics of the retinal arteroles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our ISBI 2019 was accepted for oral presentation!</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2019-03-24-isbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2019-03-24-isbi/</guid>
      <description>Our paper on photoreceptor segmentation in retinal OCT scans was accepted for oral presentation at ISBI 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>