<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on José Ignacio Orlando</title>
    <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on José Ignacio Orlando</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 José Ignacio Orlando</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fue, es y será con Tod:sunny:s</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/todos-2019-08-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/todos-2019-08-12/</guid>
      <description>Ayer hubo PASO en todo el país y el Frente de Tod☀️s</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our paper was accepted for IJCARS!</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2019-07-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2019-07-30/</guid>
      <description>Our paper entitled &amp;ldquo;Improving realism in patient specific Ultrasound simulation using CycleGANs&amp;rdquo; has been accepted for publication in the International Journal of Computer Assisted Radiology and Surgery (IJCARS)! In this article we present a hybrid approach towards US simulation that combines ray-casting techniques with CycleGANs. The key idea is to use these generative models to alleviate the drawback of current available simulation techniques. In particular, traditional ray-casting based solutions for US simulation usually fail to model complex features such as artifacts or attenuations that are typical from this imaging modality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our paper was accepted for MICCAI!</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2019-06-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2019-06-05/</guid>
      <description>Our paper entitled &amp;ldquo;Multiclass segmentation as multitask learning for drusen segmentation in retinal optical coherence tomography&amp;rdquo; has been accepted for publication at MICCAI 2019! Drusen segmentation in OCT is a challenging task. In general, it is posed either as a binary segmentation problem (drusen vs. everything else) or as a layer segmentation problem (by detecting the outer boundary of the RPE and the Bruch&amp;rsquo;s membrane). Each approach has its advantages and disadvantages: binary segmentation might be prone to false positives in areas that are not anatomically plausible, while layer segmentation might fail under the presence of large drusenoid deposits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two papers accepted for ISBI 2019!</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-12-18-isbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-12-18-isbi/</guid>
      <description>Excellent news to finish an amazing year of work at OPTIMA! We got two papers accepted for presentation at ISBI 2019 :)
&amp;ldquo;U2-Net: A Bayesian U-Net model with epistemic uncertainty feedback for photoreceptor layer segmentation in pathological OCT scans&amp;rdquo; describes a novel U-shaped architecture for photoreceptor layer segmentation in OCT scans. We modified the basic U-Net with LeakyReLUs, batch normalization and dropout to improve the original segmentation performance. Additionally, we used epistemic uncertainty estimation based on Monte Carlo sampling with dropout on test time to provide qualitative feedback about potential errors of the network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation at UBA</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-12-07-uba-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-12-07-uba-presentation/</guid>
      <description>In December 7th I gave a lecture on machine learning for ophthalmic image analysis at the University of Buenos Aires (UBA, Argentina). This talk was part of the closure event of the &amp;ldquo;Deep Learning for Medical Image Analysis&amp;rdquo; course that Enzo Ferrante taught at the Faculty of Exact Sciences. Thanks Enzo for the invitation!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REFUGE: Retinal Fundus Glaucoma Challenge</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-07-24-refuge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-07-24-refuge/</guid>
      <description>We kindly invite you to participate in the REFUGE challenge on glaucoma detection in fundus images, as part of the Ophthalmic Medical Image Analysis (OMIA) workshop at MICCAI 2018 in Granada (Spain).
The deadline for submitting your results on the validation set either for glaucoma detection, optic disc/cup segmentation and/or fovea detection is this Friday 28th!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our paper was accepted for MICCAI 2018!</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-05-25-miccai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-05-25-miccai/</guid>
      <description>Our paper entitled &amp;ldquo;Towards a glaucoma risk index based on simulated hemodynamics from fundus images&amp;rdquo; has been accepted for presentation in MICCAI 2018! In this article we present one of the first attempts to characterize the hemodynamics of the retinal arterioles og glaucomatous patients. To this end, we have used a 0D model for simulating the blood flow in patient specific segmentations of the arteries, and proposed a novel dictionary-learning based strategy for summarizing all the hemodynamic outcomes into a fixed length feature vector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NVIDIA Hardware Grant</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-02-14-nvidia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-02-14-nvidia/</guid>
      <description>My application for the NVIDIA GPU Grant was accepted! As part of this grant, I will receive a NVIDIA Titan XP GPU to perform my research on deep learning techniques for OCT image analysis. I would really like to thank the NVIDIA Corporation for providing me with this cutting-edge hardware that will certainly help me to improve the efficiency of my methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to Vienna!</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-01-01-optima/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2018-01-01-optima/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m glad to tell you, guys, that since next week I will be formally part of the Christian Doppler Laboratory for Ophthalmic Image Analysis (OPTIMA), a multidisciplinary research team that belongs to the Department of Ophthalmology and Optometry of the Medical University of Vienna (Austria). I&amp;rsquo;m joining the laboratory as a Postdoctoral Research Associate, working on automated OCT image analysis using deep learning techniques. My research will be funded by the project WWTF AugUniWien / FA746A0249.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve defended my PhD thesis!</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2017-09-22-phd-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2017-09-22-phd-defense/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, September 21th 2017, I have officially defended my PhD thesis!! It was entitled &amp;ldquo;Machine learning for ophthalmic screening and diagnostics from fundus images&amp;rdquo;. You can find its English version here, and the Spanish version here. Most of the code of each of the contributions is available on my github profile. Feel free to clone the repositories and experiment with them!
I would like to thank my supervisors, Matthew and Mariana, for guiding me through all this years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our ISBI 2019 was accepted for oral presentation!</title>
      <link>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2019-03-24-isbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ignaciorlando.github.io/post/news-2019-03-24-isbi/</guid>
      <description>Our paper on photoreceptor segmentation in retinal OCT scans was accepted for oral presentation at ISBI 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>